ecologyfund.com 2012-05-23

# EcologyFund.com, Privacy Policy - save, protect, preserve wilderness and rainforest for free!

Privacy Policy

CharityUSA.com, LLC, owners and operators of the GreaterGood Network, which includes The Hunger Site and The Hunger Site store, The Breast Cancer Site and The Breast Cancer Site store, The Child Health Site and The Child Health Site store, The Literacy Site and The Literacy Site store, The Rainforest Site and The Rainforest Site store, The Animal Rescue Site and The Animal Rescue Site store, Pink Ribbon Store, Global Girlfriend, Museum Shop, Ecology Fund, and GreaterGood.com, has created this privacy statement to spell out our commitment to individual privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices.

CharityUSA respects the privacy of its visitors. We do not sell, rent, trade, or share Personally Identifiable Information with third parties except as disclosed within this privacy statement.

CharityUSA is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent organization whose mission is to build user's trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the following websites: greatergood.com, thehungersite.com and shop.thehungersite.com, thebreastcancersite.com and shop.thebreastcancersite.com, thechildhealthsite.com and shop.thechildhealthsite.com, theliteracysite.com and shop.theliteracysite.com, therainforestsite.com and shop.therainforestsite.com, theanimalrescuesite.com and shop.theanimalrescuesite.com, globalgirlfriend.com, pinkribbonstore.com, museumshop.com, and ecologyfund.com (collectively "the Sites"). Because CharityUSA wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact [customerservice@greatergood.com](mailto:customerservice@greatergood.com). If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at [http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns.

* * *

### Daily Click Sites

Clicking on the "Click Here to Give" button on the home page of The Hunger Site, The Breast Cancer Site, The Animal Rescue Site, and all of our other Click-to-Give sites is free to the visitor. 100% of the money from sponsor advertising is given to the charity partners of each site by GreaterGood.org. You are not required to provide any personal information to visit our suite of GreaterGood Network sites or to make your daily, free click.

Site visitors may also help protect animals or people by signing petitions or taking actions which attempt to influence legislation or convince the targets of the campaigns to act differently. Site visitors may voluntarily provide personal information to sign a "Take Action!" campaign, share a story, photograph, testimonial or other comment with the GreaterGood Network community, sign up for an e-newsletter or click reminder e-mails, or to participate in other site activities as we offer them. See below for how we use this information.

#### Take Action Campaigns

Signing a "Take Action!" campaign gives you a method to impact public policy in ways that connect to the core issues of our Click-to-Give sites. When you sign a "Take Action!" campaign at any one of the GreaterGood Network sites, you are required to provide certain personal information such as name, e-mail address and sometimes street address so it can be shared with the target of the campaign in order to influence the outcome of legislation or change policies in order to help people or animals. This personal information is required to validate your campaign signature. All personal information you provide when signing a petition or participating in a "Take Action!" campaign, including name, address, city, state, country, and comments are considered public information and will be provided to the target of the campaign (for example, sending a letter and petition to the Surgeon General). Specific targets for a campaign will be clearly identified within each campaign. Your city, state, country, and comments will also be visible on the Click-to-Give site(s) associated with the campaign. Your name will also be visible on the site unless you have checked the "Do not display my name" checkbox at the time of signing. We will not display street or e-mail addresses entered into the proper "E-mail" or "Address" fields during signing. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these campaigns.

CharityUSA hosts two kinds of campaigns: campaigns sponsored by its own suite of cause sites and campaigns sponsored by nonprofits. At the time of signing you will have an opportunity to indicate whether or not you wish to receive communication from any third-party nonprofit sponsor of the campaign. If you do not opt-out of such communications, CharityUSA will send your contact information to the third-party nonprofit sponsoring the campaign. If you opt-out of receiving such online offers, CharityUSA will not share your name, e-mail address, or other signing information with the nonprofit sponsor.

#### Share Your Story/Visitor Testimonials/Comments/Reviews

When we post visitor stories, testimonials, comments, or reviews on our web site, these may contain personally identifiable information such as name, city, and state. We obtain consent in the submission form prior to posting the story, testimonial, comment, or review. At the time of submission you may also choose the "Do not display my name" option, which will replace your name with "Anonymous".

* * *

### Communications from the Site

#### E-cards & E-mail Product to a Friend

If you choose to send an e-card or e-mail a product description to a friend, we will ask you for your name and e-mail address, and for your recipient's name and e-mail address. We will automatically send your chosen recipients a one-time e-mail to view the e-card or product and to invite him or her to visit the site. CharityUSA does not store, sell, trade or otherwise use any name or e-mail address you share here for purposes other than to deliver your message.

#### E-newsletters

If you wish to subscribe to our e-newsletter(s), we will use your name and e-mail address to send a periodic e-mail to you. We provide unsubscribe options with each and every e-mail sent in this manner. This is also summarized in the "Choice and Opt-out" section.

#### Special Offers and Updates

Once you've shopped with us in one of our do-good stores, we will periodically send you information on products, services, special deals, and promotions. You may opt-out of receiving these types of communications during checkout. This is also summarized in the "Choice and Opt-out" section. Subscribers are the first to be notified of start dates of major sales and other promotions, and periodically receive subscriber-exclusive offers which are great deals and free products available only to registered users who continue to receive our updates.

#### Service-related Announcements

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an e-mail. You may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature.

#### Accounts

You do not need an account to make a daily free click or to purchase anything from our store. If you choose to create an account, we request and store your name, e-mail address, and a password to give you access to and to protect your account. We also give you an opportunity during checkout to save your billing and shipping addresses in order to provide a speedier and more convenient checkout experience in the future. We do not store any credit card data in your account.

#### Shopping

When you purchase something at one of the GreaterGood Network stores, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. During checkout, you will be asked to give your billing address, shipping address, phone number and e-mail address. We use your e-mail address to confirm your order, and in case there are any problems with your order. Phone numbers are occasionally used to communicate with you about your order only. Credit card information is encrypted and used for order billing only: we do not save your credit card information. During checkout you will be able to sign up for special offers and updates, an e-mail sent approximately once a week. You may unsubscribe at any time. Instructions for unsubscribing are included in each e-mail sent.

CharityUSA uses third parties such as a payment processor to bill you for goods and services, and in some cases a third-party drop shipping company to ship your order. For fulfillment purposes, our drop ship vendors are notified of your name, shipping, and e-mail addresses. These companies do not retain, share, store, or otherwise use personally identifiable information for any other purposes. These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for promotional purposes.

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website.

#### Gifts That Give More™

When you make an online donation by purchasing a Gift That Gives More™, we share your personal information with our nonprofit, independent partner, GreaterGood.org. You will receive your US tax receipt from GreaterGood.org upon completing your donation and may also receive a direct donation appeal from GreaterGood.org. 100% of the money you contribute via a Gift That Gives More™ is given to GreaterGood.org to be used for the purposes specified; we even cover bank and credit card charges in order to ensure that 100% goes to the charitable purpose you intend. Information about which organizations are granted money contributed through the Gift That Gives More™ program is available on the GreaterGood.org website.

* * *

### Links/Electronic Log Files/Cookies

Each of our sites contains links to other sites, including sponsor sites and other philanthropic sites. CharityUSA is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such sites and encourages you to review these companies' privacy policies.

#### Log Files

As is true of most sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in electronic log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information. We use this information to understand how our websites are used to better meet the needs of our visitors and customers. We use IP address to identify and block malicious behavior like click fraud or denial of service attacks.

#### Cookies

You do not have to accept cookies in order to click and have your click count, or to shop with us.

We use electronic cookies to recognize your computer as a returning visitor. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. Our sites use cookies to keep track of your shopping cart. If you have entered something into your shopping cart on a previous visit, your cookie saves these items for your return visit. We cookie customer order IDs, and protect this information by encrypting it, and we delete the cookie upon successful order authorization.

You may disable cookies from your browser's configuration menu at any time. All cookie information is considered personal and proprietary, and is encompassed in our commitment to your privacy and security of data. For enhanced site visitor experience, we also use a cookie to store your click history. This would only be used to display your click history to you and is purely optional. In addition, some of our business partners use cookies in the process of displaying their sponsor ads. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by this Site only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties.

In any case, you are not required to accept cookies to click.

#### Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

We employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence.

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see "Choice and Opt-out."

* * *

### Security

Your comfort and security while shopping with us are important. We have multiple ways of protecting our customers:

  1. We do not save or store your credit card number.

For your protection, we do not keep your credit card information on file ever, even if you have an account. When you make an order, your billing information is securely transmitted to our credit card processor, Litle & Co. of Massachusetts, which we selected because of its concern for data security. Litle & Co. processes all charges to your credit card. Litle & Co. adheres to the highest standards to protect your information. We follow their example in keeping our systems up-to-date and secure. We actively test for vulnerabilities. Our security measures and internal processes are designed to ensure that your billing information is kept secure while we process your order and that your privacy is protected.

  2. We use 256-bit encryption, the highest level of Internet security currently available.

Now there is an easy and reliable way to know you can trust that our stores are secure. In Microsoft Windows® Internet Explorer® 7 and 8, and Mozilla Firefox®, the address bar turns green and displays our name. The security status bar shows that the transaction is encrypted and we have been authenticated according to the most rigorous industry standard.

Please note: Charges will appear on your credit card statement under the name of the storefront you first entered through:

The Hunger Site  
The Breast Cancer Site  
The Child Health Site  
The Literacy Site  
The Rainforest Site  
The Animal Rescue Site  
Global Girlfriend  
Pink Ribbon Shop  
Museum Shop

If we cannot identify which storefront you entered through, charges will appear on your statement as CharityUSA.com, LLC.

PayPal receipts indicate CharityUSA.com, LLC.

Ordering online with us is secure and easy. If you have any concerns about ordering online, please feel free to place your order with our customer service department by phone. Hours are 10:30 am to 6:00 pm (ET), Monday through Friday. You may call us toll-free within the U.S. and Canada at 1-888-355-4321. To contact us from outside the U.S. and Canada, please call (206) 268-5401.

#### Collection of Personal Information from Children

CharityUSA.com, LLC does not knowingly collect individually identifiable information from or about children under 13. If CharityUSA.com, LLC later learns that we have personally identifiable information about a child under 13, we will take steps to remove that child's information from our databases. If you have questions or concerns please contact us at (206) 859-5201 or by e-mail: [customerservice@greatergood.com](mailto:customerservice@greatergood.com).

#### Updating/Accessing/Amending/Correcting Personally Identifiable Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, you may contact us to amend or correct it. We will respond to your request within 1 business day. See below for our contact information.

#### Choice/Opt-out

We provide you the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product/service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference on our order form.

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by contacting us at:

GreaterGood Network Customer Service  
One Union Square  
600 University Street, Suite 1000  
Seattle, WA 98101-4107  
U.S.A.  

U.S. and Canada: 1-888-355-4321  
Outside the U.S. and Canada: 206-268-5401  
Customer Service hours are 10:30 am to 6:00 pm (ET), Monday through Friday

You will be notified if your personal information is collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider other than as specified in this policy, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party. Although there are no plans to do this presently, if this ever occurs, an opt-out will be provided to you before any personally identifiable information is shared, so it is always your choice when information is provided to a third party.

#### Changes to this Privacy Statement

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here or by e-mail.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on April 12, 2010.

**Suggestions or comments?** Write us! [Feedback@EcologyFund.com](mailto:Feedback@EcologyFund.com).
